import { Quiz } from "@/utils/types";

export const quizContent: Quiz[] = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "What was the name of the band where Vangelis played during his student years?",
    options: ["The Forminx", "Aphrodite's Child", "Socrates", "The Minis"],
    reason:
      "The Forminx were active between about 1962 and 1966, performing several concerts in Greece and releasing 9 singles.",
    answer: "The Forminx",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question:
      "The first composition which brought Vangelis international fame, was...",
    options: [
      "Rain and Tears",
      "Spring, Summer, Winter and Fall",
      "I Hear You Now",
      "I'll Find My Way Home",
    ],
    reason:
      "It was released as an Aphrodite's Child single in May 1968, topping the chart in France.",
    answer: "Rain and Tears",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      'Before its release, Aphrodite\'s Child album "666" was parked for more than a year, because...',
    options: [
      "the record company considered the track Infinity pornographic, and wanted to remove it from the album.",
      "the record company went bankrupt after the completion of the studio sessions.",
      "an earlier release would have collided with Jesus Christ Superstar.",
      "the band asked for more time to organize a promotional concert tour.",
    ],
    reason:
      "As a compromise, Vangelis shortened the track to 5 minutes, and the album was released in 1972.",
    answer:
      "the record company considered the track Infinity pornographic, and wanted to remove it from the album.",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      'What kind of extra material is included in the remastered 4CD "666" box set (2024)?',
    options: [
      "The remastered 1974 Greek LP version",
      "Live performances by Aphrodite's Child",
      "An extended version of the track Infinity",
      "A poster with Vangelis signature",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "The remastered 1974 Greek LP version",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question:
      '"Fais que ton rêve soit plus long que la nuit" is a 1972 album of Vangelis, which was inspired by...',
    options: [
      "the events in Paris, May 1968",
      "a French cabaret show",
      "Vangelis' habit to wake up late",
      "an ancient Orphic hymn, written to Night",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "the events in Paris, May 1968",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "Which unofficial albums were withdrawn from distribution, on Vangelis' demand?",
    options: [
      "The Dragon and Hypothesis",
      "Sex Power and Poeme Symphonique",
      "Inner Data and Symphony no. 3",
      "Silent Portraits and The Bounty",
    ],
    reason:
      "Both albums were released on LP in the 1970s, and sold in large quantities without Vangelis' permission.",
    answer: "The Dragon and Hypothesis",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "Vangelis plays a Hohner Clavinet on this album.",
    options: ["Earth", "Soil Festivities", "Voices", "Alexander"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Earth",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "The portrait of Vangelis is seen on the front sleeve of this album.",
    options: ["Earth", "Alexander", "El Greco", "Blade Runner"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Earth",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "La Petite Fille de la Mer from the L'Apocalypse des Animaux album…",
    options: [
      "is featured on many Vangelis compilation albums",
      "is the first space-themed track by Vangelis",
      "contains a flugelhorn performance by a friend of Vangelis",
      "is a short track of merely one minute",
    ],
    reason:
      "From the same album, Creation du Monde is the space-themed track, La Singe Bleu has flugelhorn, and L'Ours Musicien is just one minute long.",
    answer: "is featured on many Vangelis compilation albums",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      "In which year was the soundtrack Entends-tu les chiens aboyer (a.k.a Ignacio) originally released?",
    options: ["1975", "1985", "1995", "2004"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "1975",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question:
      "Which statement is NOT true? Heaven And Hell was Vangelis' first album…",
    options: [
      "released on Polydor label",
      "recorded at Nemo Studios, London",
      "featuring a collaboration with Jon Anderson",
      "omitting his surname Papathanassiou on the sleeve",
    ],
    reason: "H&H was released on RCA label.",
    answer: "released on Polydor label",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question:
      "Which Vangelis track was used as the title music for Carl Sagan's documentary series Cosmos (1980)?",
    options: [
      "Symphony to the Powers B, movement 3",
      "Creation du Monde",
      "The Motion of Stars",
      "Return to the Void",
    ],
    reason: "Taken from the album Heaven and Hell.",
    answer: "Symphony to the Powers B, movement 3",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question: "Which oriental instrument is used on the album Albedo 0.39?",
    options: ["Gamelan", "Koto", "Shakuhachi", "Gong"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Gamelan",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question:
      "On the track Albedo 0.39, the astronomical figures are read by...",
    options: [
      "Keith Spencer-Allen",
      "Vangelis",
      "Carl Sagan",
      "an uncredited visitor of the Nemo studios",
    ],
    reason:
      "Spencer-Allen was the recording engineer for the Albedo 0.39 album.",
    answer: "Keith Spencer-Allen",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question:
      "Which Vangelis track won the Midem International Instrumental award?",
    options: ["To the Unknown Man", "Himalaya", "Suffocation", "Réve"],
    reason: "From the album Spiral (1977).",
    answer: "To the Unknown Man",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question: "Which documentary about Vangelis was released on DVD?",
    options: [
      "Vangelis and the Journey to Ithaka",
      "Vangelis – L'Arbre de Vie",
      "Vangelis – The Man and his Music",
      "Vangelis – Musique au Coeur",
    ],
    reason: "Directed by Tony Palmer.",
    answer: "Vangelis and the Journey to Ithaka",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question:
      "Vangelis composed lots of music for Frederic Rossif's documentaries. Which score has NOT been released as a standalone album?",
    options: [
      "Sauvage et Beau",
      "L'Apocalypse des Animaux",
      "La Féte Sauvage",
      "Opera Sauvage",
    ],
    reason:
      "Only the title track has been released on the Portraits compilation album.",
    answer: "Sauvage et Beau",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question:
      "Which was the first Vangelis album to feature the iconic Yamaha CS-80 synthesizer?",
    options: ["Spiral", "Heaven And Hell", "Beaubourg", "China"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Spiral",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "Which film score earned Vangelis the Academy Award (Oscar)?",
    options: [
      "Chariots of Fire",
      "Blade Runner",
      "1492 - Conquest of Paradise",
      "The Bounty",
    ],
    reason: "Best Film Score, 1982.",
    answer: "Chariots of Fire",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question:
      "In which studio was the 1492 - Conquest of Paradise soundtrack recorded?",
    options: [
      "Epsilon Laboratory, Paris",
      "Nemo Studios, London",
      "Sound Studios, Athens",
      "Forum Studios, Rome",
    ],
    reason: "It was a rooftop studio with glass walls and ceiling.",
    answer: "Epsilon Laboratory, Paris",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question:
      "Which album does NOT feature the English Chamber Choir, led by Guy Protheroe?",
    options: [
      "Mythodea",
      "Heaven And Hell",
      "Mask",
      "1492 - Conquest of Paradise",
    ],
    reason: "Mythodea features The National Opera of Greece Choir.",
    answer: "Mythodea",
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question:
      "At the opening ceremony of the 6th World Championships in Athletics (1997), Vangelis performed two songs with...",
    options: [
      "Montserrat Caballé",
      "Maria Farantouri",
      "Markella Hatziano",
      "Melina Mercouri",
    ],
    reason:
      "March with Me and The Prayer, released on Caballé compilation albums with a third collaboration track, Like a Dream.",
    answer: "Montserrat Caballé",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question:
      "This Jon and Vangelis song was only released on the rare US version of the Page of Life album.",
    options: [
      "Change We Must",
      "Be a Good Friend of Mine",
      "Journey to Ixtlan",
      "Sing With Your Eyes",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Change We Must",
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: "Which album's artwork features an animal?",
    options: [
      "Soil Festivities",
      "Invisible Connections",
      "Oceanic",
      "Opera Sauvage",
    ],
    reason: "A great diving beetle is seen on the sleeve.",
    answer: "Soil Festivities",
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question: "Which instrument of Vangelis is a digital synthesizer?",
    options: ["Roland JD800", "Korg KR-55", "Roland Juno 106", "Yamaha CS-80"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Roland JD800",
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: "What was the location of the Mythodea concert in 2001?",
    options: [
      "Temple of (Olympian) Zeus, Athens",
      "Herodion theatre, Athens",
      "Panathinaiko stadium, Athens",
      "Zappeion Hall, Athens",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Temple of (Olympian) Zeus, Athens",
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question: "Which Vangelis album was NOT nominated for Grammy?",
    options: ["Voices", "Chariots of Fire", "Oceanic", "Rosetta"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Voices",
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: "The album Beaubourg was inspired by...",
    options: [
      "a modern art museum",
      "the view on the old city from Vangelis' childhood house",
      "the nearest metro station to Vangelis' studio",
      "Vangelis' favourite restaurant",
    ],
    reason: "The Pompidou Centre is located in the Beaubourg area of Paris.",
    answer: "a modern art museum",
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: "Vangelis practiced this sport as a hobby.",
    options: ["Archery", "Box", "Chess", "Skating"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Archery",
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: "The album Juno to Jupiter was dedicated to...",
    options: [
      "Vangelis' brother, Niko Papathanassiou",
      "Vangelis' father, Ulysses",
      "the mission team of the European Space Agency",
      "Melia",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Vangelis' brother, Niko Papathanassiou",
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question: "Vangelis' iconic Yamaha CS-80 synthesizer is NOT...",
    options: [
      "digital",
      "polyphonic",
      "velocity-sensitive",
      "aftertouch-sensitive",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "digital",
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: "Which Jon and Vangelis song takes up a full LP side?",
    options: [
      "Horizon",
      "A Play Within a Play",
      "State of Independence",
      "Money",
    ],
    reason: "From the album Private Collection (1983).",
    answer: "Horizon",
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: "In which city did Vangelis live, in his final years?",
    options: ["Paris", "Athens", "London", "Volos"],
    reason: "Vangelis lived in Paris from about 2009 to his death in 2022.",
    answer: "Paris",
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: "Which track was released as a single from the album China?",
    options: ["The Long March", "The Tao of Love", "Himalaya", "The Dragon"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "The Long March",
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: "The track Réve from the album Opera Sauvage...",
    options: [
      "is performed on Fender Rhodes electric piano",
      "is the shortest on the album",
      "features acoustic guitar",
      "features a guest performance on harp by Jon Anderson",
    ],
    reason:
      "From the same album, Chromatique has acoustic guitar (probably played by Raphael Preston), while Jon Anderson plays harp on Flamants Roses.",
    answer: "is performed on Fender Rhodes electric piano",
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question:
      "Which was the first Vangelis compilation album to contain previously unreleased tracks?",
    options: ["Themes", "Gift", "Light and Shadow", "Reprise"],
    reason:
      "Themes was released in 1989 and contained five previously unreleased tracks from the films Missing, Blade Runner and The Bounty.",
    answer: "Themes",
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: "Which was the last, released film score by Vangelis?",
    options: [
      "Swiadectwo (Testimony)",
      "Crépuscule des ombres (Twilight of Shadows)",
      "El Greco",
      "Juno to Jupiter",
    ],
    reason:
      "Swiadectwo was released in 2008, one year after the El Greco soundtrack. Crépuscule is a later score, which however has not been released. Juno to Jupiter is not a film score.",
    answer: "Swiadectwo (Testimony)",
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: "Which track has an official release in CD format?",
    options: [
      "To the Unknown Man, part 2",
      "Silent Portraits",
      "Cosmos Autopator",
      "The Long March, part 2",
    ],
    reason: "Added on the remastered Spiral CD, 2013.",
    answer: "To the Unknown Man, part 2",
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question:
      "Vangelis ramped down the Nemo studios, and returned to Greece in...",
    options: ["1987", "1978", "1992", "2008"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "1987",
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: "Who was the sound engineer of the Blade Runner score (in 1982)?",
    options: [
      "Raine Shine",
      "Keith Spencer-Allen",
      "Raphael Preston",
      "Jess Sutcliffe",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Raine Shine",
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question: "How many collaboration album(s) Vangelis and Irene Papas have?",
    options: [
      "2",
      "1",
      "3",
      "Their only collaboration is the track Infinity on Aphrodite's Child 666 album",
    ],
    reason: "Odes (1979) and Rapsodies (1986).",
    answer: "2",
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question: "The track Racines on the Odes album…",
    options: [
      "is an original instrumental composition by Vangelis",
      "contains three different musical themes",
      "features an a cappella performance by Irene Papas",
      "describes a murder of jealousy",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "is an original instrumental composition by Vangelis",
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question:
      "Which Jon and Vangelis album had the best chart performance in the UK?",
    options: [
      "Short Stories",
      "The Friend of Mr Cairo",
      "Private Collection",
      "Page of Life",
    ],
    reason: "Short Stories peaked at no. 4 in January 1980.",
    answer: "Short Stories",
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: "Suffocation (from See You Later album) was inspired by...",
    options: [
      "the industrial accident in Seveso",
      "Vangelis' feeling toward the record company",
      "a tempest on the English Channel, dissuading Vangelis from crossing",
      "a military exhibition in London, showcasing gas masks",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "the industrial accident in Seveso",
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question:
      "The title music for Chariots of Fire was originally planned to be...",
    options: [
      "L'Enfant (from Opera Sauvage)",
      "Hymne (from Opera Sauvage)",
      "an orchestral score",
      "To the Unknown Man (from Spiral)",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "L'Enfant (from Opera Sauvage)",
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question:
      "Which musician sued Vangelis for plagiarism, regarding the Chariots of Fire title music?",
    options: [
      "Stavros Logarides",
      "Michel Huygens",
      "Peter Marsh",
      "Robert Fitoussi",
    ],
    reason:
      "The trial was held in London in February 1987. Vangelis was acquitted.",
    answer: "Stavros Logarides",
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question:
      "Which track was NOT part of the first edition of The Friends of Mr Cairo album (1981)?",
    options: [
      "I'll Find My Way Home",
      "State of Independence",
      "The Mayflower",
      "Back to School",
    ],
    reason:
      "I'll Find My Way Home was released in the end of 1981, and added to the subsequent releases of the Mr. Cairo album.",
    answer: "I'll Find My Way Home",
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    question: "The track Friends of Mr Cairo was inspired by...",
    options: [
      "old Hollywood movies",
      "Jon Anderson's vacation in Egypt",
      "muslim friends of Vangelis, with whom he often met at his favourite restaurant in London",
      "the CS-80 synth of Vangelis, nicknamed Mr Cairo",
    ],
    reason: "Notably The Maltese Falcon and The Thief of Baghdad.",
    answer: "old Hollywood movies",
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    question: "The lyrics of the track Italian Song are in this language.",
    options: ["constructed language", "English", "Italian", "Latin"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "constructed language",
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question:
      "Who is Deborah (inspiring the song on the Private Collection album)?",
    options: [
      "Jon Anderson's daughter, Vangelis' godchild",
      "Vangelis' girlfiend at the time",
      "Jon Anderson's wife",
      "Vangelis' contact at Spheric B.V. publishing company",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Jon Anderson's daughter, Vangelis' godchild",
  },
  {
    id: 51,
    question: "When did Vangelis release the album Soil Festivities?",
    options: ["1984", "1988", "1992", "1996"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "1984",
  },
  {
    id: 52,
    question: "Which choir sings (uncredited) on the album Mask?",
    options: [
      "English Chamber Choir, led by Guy Protheroe",
      "National Opera of Greece Choir, led by Blake Neely",
      "Choir of the Greek Radio and Television, led by Irina Valentinova",
      "Guillaume Tell Choir, led by Nic Raine",
    ],
    reason:
      "Guy Protheroe has a solo performance in Movement 4, while Julia Field of ECC sings solo in Movement 1.",
    answer: "English Chamber Choir, led by Guy Protheroe",
  },
  {
    id: 53,
    question:
      "Which music is used during the opening titles of the film Antarctica?",
    options: [
      "Other Side of Antarctica",
      "Theme from Antarctica",
      "Antarctic Echoes",
      "Song of White",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Other Side of Antarctica",
  },
  {
    id: 54,
    question: "Which Vangelis album has 4 tracks?",
    options: [
      "There is no such album",
      "Heaven And Hell",
      "Spiral",
      "Invisible Connections",
    ],
    reason:
      "Somewhat surprising, as he has albums with 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 etc tracks.",
    answer: "There is no such album",
  },
  {
    id: 55,
    question:
      "How many original albums did Vangelis release, recorded at Nemo studios (incl. collaborations with Jon Anderson and Irene Papas)?",
    options: [
      "18 (excl. Blade Runner)",
      "10 (excl. Blade Runner)",
      "12 (excl. Blade Runner)",
      "14 (excl. Blade Runner)",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "18 (excl. Blade Runner)",
  },
  {
    id: 56,
    question: "Beside composing, what was Vangelis' other main activity?",
    options: ["Painting", "Aviation", "Poetry", "Scuba diving"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Painting",
  },
  {
    id: 57,
    question: "Which record company did Vangelis work with?",
    options: [
      "All three",
      "Universal Music Group",
      "Warner Music Group",
      "Sony Music Group",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "All three",
  },
  {
    id: 58,
    question: "Which Vangelis concert was released on LP/CD?",
    options: [
      "There is no official LP or CD with live material",
      "Opening the Katara Amphitheater, Doha",
      "The Night of Poetry, Athens",
      "Eureka concert, Rotterdam",
    ],
    reason:
      "The Mythodea concert (2001) has been released on DVD, but its audio track was recorded in a concert hall.",
    answer: "There is no official LP or CD with live material",
  },
  {
    id: 59,
    question: "Who was the sound engineer of the last 3 Vangelis albums?",
    options: [
      "Philippe Colonna",
      "Frédérick Rousseau",
      "Vangelis Saitis",
      "Vangelis himself",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Philippe Colonna",
  },
  {
    id: 60,
    question: "The Invisible Connections album (1985)...",
    options: [
      "is experimental",
      "is romantic",
      "is orchestral",
      "has a steady beat",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "is experimental",
  },
  {
    id: 61,
    question: "Which song of the Rapsodies album deals with resurrection?",
    options: [
      "Christos anesti",
      "Ti ipermacho stratigo",
      "Rapsodia",
      "Asma Asmaton",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Christos anesti",
  },
  {
    id: 62,
    question: "Which statement is NOT true? The Rapsodies album…",
    options: [
      "contains 19th century Greek folk songs in modern arrangement",
      "was Vangelis' last collaboration album with Irene Papas",
      "was the last album recorded at Nemo Studios",
      "was released on Polydor label",
    ],
    reason:
      "Rapsodies contains mostly Greek/Byzantine liturgic music. The other Vangelis/Papas collaboration album, Odes, has folk songs.",
    answer: "contains 19th century Greek folk songs in modern arrangement",
  },
  {
    id: 63,
    question: "Which movement of Soil Festivities is the longest?",
    options: ["First", "Second", "Fourth", "Fifth"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "First",
  },
  {
    id: 64,
    question: "How did Vangelis celebrate the release of The City album?",
    options: [
      "He gave a party in his Athens residence to the local Warner staff.",
      "He visited the red lights quarter in Tokyo.",
      "He invited Roman Polanski and Emmanuelle Seigner to his beach house.",
      "He refurbished the Mega Studio with new equipment.",
    ],
    reason: "This was in November 1990, at his home/studio at Meleagrou 9.",
    answer:
      "He gave a party in his Athens residence to the local Warner staff.",
  },
  {
    id: 65,
    question: "Vangelis was a jury member at which film festival (1991)?",
    options: [
      "Cannes Film Festival",
      "Venice Film Festival",
      "Berlin International Film Festival",
      "Brussels Film Festival",
    ],
    reason: "Invited by his friend, Roman Polanski, who was head of the jury.",
    answer: "Cannes Film Festival",
  },
  {
    id: 66,
    question:
      "What is the connection between Vangelis and the new Acropolis museum in Athens?",
    options: [
      "Vangelis' house was planned to be demolished, as it blocked the view from the museum terrace to the Acropolis.",
      "Vangelis was elected as an honorary curator.",
      "Vangelis donated several artifacts to the museum.",
      "The museum was allowed to sell hand-signed Vangelis CDs.",
    ],
    reason:
      "The demolition plan was eventually cancelled by the Greek Council of State in 2009.",
    answer:
      "Vangelis' house was planned to be demolished, as it blocked the view from the museum terrace to the Acropolis.",
  },
  {
    id: 67,
    question: "Where was the Mythodea album recorded?",
    options: [
      "At the Megaron Concert Hall in Athens",
      "It was recorded live at the Mythodea concert in Athens",
      "In Epsilon studio, Paris, many years before its release",
      "At the home studio of the London Metropolitan Orchestra",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "At the Megaron Concert Hall in Athens",
  },
  {
    id: 68,
    question: "Vangelis did NOT have a studio in this country.",
    options: ["Spain", "France", "Greece", "United Kingdom"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Spain",
  },
  {
    id: 69,
    question: "What was Vangelis' opinion on new age music?",
    options: [
      "It is a style which gave the opportunity for untalented people to make very boring music.",
      "New age music and my albums have a lot of common roots.",
      "I've been constantly monitoring and inspired by the new age music scene.",
      "I am enthusiastic about New Age spiritualism, and music which is suitable for meditation and healing.",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer:
      "It is a style which gave the opportunity for untalented people to make very boring music.",
  },
  {
    id: 70,
    question: "Which statement is NOT correct?",
    options: [
      "The El Greco soundtrack album has a Greco painting on its front sleeve.",
      "The Foros Timis ston Greco studio album has been sold by the National Gallery of Athens.",
      "The El Greco soundtrack contains compositions from other Greek musicians.",
      "The El Greco studio album has movements performed by opera singers.",
    ],
    reason:
      "The soundtrack album only bears the El Greco insciption on its front sleeve. The El Greco studio album features a work of the painter.",
    answer:
      "The El Greco soundtrack album has a Greco painting on its front sleeve.",
  },
  {
    id: 71,
    question: "One of these 1992 films does NOT have a Vangelis score.",
    options: [
      "Scent of a Woman",
      "The Plague",
      "Bitter Moon",
      "1492 - Conquest of Paradise",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Scent of a Woman",
  },
  {
    id: 72,
    question: "Which album was NOT released in Yugoslavian pressing?",
    options: [
      "The Friends of Mr Cairo",
      "Short Stories",
      "Chariots of Fire",
      "Themes",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "The Friends of Mr Cairo",
  },
  {
    id: 73,
    question: "Which album has an official release in vinyl format?",
    options: [
      "El Greco soundtrack album",
      "Voices",
      "Oceanic",
      "El Greco studio album",
    ],
    reason:
      "It seems that in the second half of the 1990s Warner Music considered the LP format outdated.",
    answer: "El Greco soundtrack album",
  },
  {
    id: 74,
    question: "Who plays saxophone on the BR 25 album?",
    options: [
      "Dimitris Tsakas",
      "Dick Morrissey",
      "Michel Ripoche",
      "Vasilis Saleas",
    ],
    reason:
      "On memorable tracks Sweet Solitude, Dimitri's Bar, Perfume Exotico.",
    answer: "Dimitris Tsakas",
  },
  {
    id: 75,
    question:
      'Which track of the Blade Runner Trilogy album is referred to as an "Alternate Love Theme", heard in an early work print of the Blade Runner movie?',
    options: [
      "Desolation Path",
      "One More Kiss, Dear",
      "Empty Streets",
      "Tears in Rain",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Desolation Path",
  },
  {
    id: 76,
    question: "The Direct album took its name from...",
    options: [
      "Vangelis' new recording device, eliminating the overdubs",
      "Vangelis' desire to maintain closer relations with his fans",
      "Some digital synthesizers were powered by direct current",
      "the most accessible (title) track on the album",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Vangelis' new recording device, eliminating the overdubs",
  },
  {
    id: 77,
    question: "Which of these Vangelis soundtracks has had an album release?",
    options: ["Blade Runner", "Missing", "The Bounty", "Bitter Moon"],
    reason:
      "From the other films only the title music has been released on Vanglis compilation albums.",
    answer: "Blade Runner",
  },
  {
    id: 78,
    question:
      "Which album can be counted to the 'Direct' series, announced by BMG Arista?",
    options: [
      "Direct remains the only Vangelis solo album released by Arista",
      "Reprise",
      "Invisible Connections",
      "Rosetta",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Direct remains the only Vangelis solo album released by Arista",
  },
  {
    id: 79,
    question:
      "Which track of the Page of Life album was originally written for the Francesco film?",
    options: [
      "Shine for Me",
      "Page of Life",
      "Garden of Senses",
      "Anyone Can Light a Candle",
    ],
    reason:
      "An instrumental version of the track is heard during the end titles of the film.",
    answer: "Shine for Me",
  },
  {
    id: 80,
    question: "Which album sleeve was NOT designed by Vangelis?",
    options: ["Albedo 0.39", "Spiral", "China", "Opera Sauvage"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Albedo 0.39",
  },
  {
    id: 81,
    question: "Which track on The City album has Japanese voices?",
    options: ["Twilight", "Morning Papers", "Nerve Centre", "Good to See You"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Twilight",
  },
  {
    id: 82,
    question: "Who sang wordless vocals on Ballad (Spiral album)?",
    options: [
      "Vangelis himself",
      "Veronique Skawinska",
      "Jon Anderson",
      "Milva",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Vangelis himself",
  },
  {
    id: 83,
    question:
      "In which way the Conquest of Paradise (title) track is linked to the times of Columbus?",
    options: [
      "The chord progression of the verse is based on the Folia theme.",
      "The choir sings liturgical texts in it.",
      "Ridley Scott liked the track so much, that he donated a Columbus manuscript to Vangelis.",
      "Vangelis used a Renaissance harp during the recording.",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "The chord progression of the verse is based on the Folia theme.",
  },
  {
    id: 84,
    question:
      "Vangelis wrote lots of music for theatre performances. Which is the only stage score that has been released on disc?",
    options: [
      "Chariots of Fire – The Play",
      "The Beauty and the Beast",
      "The Tempest (A vihar)",
      "The Thread",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Chariots of Fire – The Play",
  },
  {
    id: 85,
    question:
      "What was the Rosetta program, inspiring the album of the same name?",
    options: [
      "The mission of the European Space Agency, to study a comet.",
      "Jean-Francois Champollion's long quest to decipher Egyptian hieroglyphs.",
      "To protect and exhibit the Rosetta stone, according to 21st century standards.",
      "Vangelis' plan to perform the same musical theme in different interpretations.",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "The mission of the European Space Agency, to study a comet.",
  },
  {
    id: 86,
    question: "Which album contains older Vangelis pieces, reworked for piano?",
    options: ["Nocturne", "L'Apocalypse des Animaux", "Mask", "Odyssey"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Nocturne",
  },
  {
    id: 87,
    question: "Which statement is true?",
    options: [
      "Vangelis preferred minimal planning and maximum spontaneity in his recordings.",
      "Vangelis learned to read and write musical notations at school.",
      "Vangelis maintained cordial relationship with the music industry.",
      "Vangelis was indifferent to ancient Greek culture.",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer:
      "Vangelis preferred minimal planning and maximum spontaneity in his recordings.",
  },
  {
    id: 88,
    question:
      'Who conceived the "Beyond: Ode to the Earth" documentary film, which juxtaposes images from space and Vangelis music?',
    options: [
      "André Kuipers, astronaut",
      "Vangelis himself",
      "Scott Bolton, NASA Principal Investigator",
      "Carl Sagan, cosmologist",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "André Kuipers, astronaut",
  },
  {
    id: 89,
    question:
      "Which track is heard during the opening titles of the 1492 - Conquest of Paradise film?",
    options: [
      "Hispanola",
      "Conquest of Paradise",
      "West Across the Ocean Sea",
      "Pinta, Nina, Santa Maria",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Hispanola",
  },
  {
    id: 90,
    question: "Which artist does NOT sing on the Voices album?",
    options: [
      "Cherry Vanilla",
      "Caroline Lavelle",
      "Paul Young",
      "Stina Nordenstam",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Cherry Vanilla",
  },
  {
    id: 91,
    question: "What was the working title of the Oceanic album?",
    options: [
      "Aquatic Stories",
      "Footlight Parade",
      "Million Dollar Mermaid",
      "Songs of the Seas",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Aquatic Stories",
  },
  {
    id: 92,
    question:
      "Can the legendary Nemo studios be visited by the fans, in London nowadays?",
    options: [
      "No. The building which housed the studio has been demolished.",
      "No. The area has been restricted due to its proximity to government buildings.",
      "Only based on admission request, submitted at least one month in advance.",
      "Yes. The control room of the studios has been converted to a small Vangelis museum.",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "No. The building which housed the studio has been demolished.",
  },
  {
    id: 93,
    question:
      "Who wrote the lyrics to the vocal version of Chariots of Fire title music (Race to the End)?",
    options: [
      "Jon Anderson",
      "Demis Roussos",
      "Costas Ferris",
      "Guy Protheroe",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Jon Anderson",
  },
  {
    id: 94,
    question:
      "Vangelis was ... years old, when he released his last album Juno to Jupiter.",
    options: ["78", "65", "71", "75"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "78",
  },
  {
    id: 95,
    question:
      'Who directed the documentary film "Nuclear Now", with original Vangelis music?',
    options: ["Oliver Stone", "Frederic Rossif", "Hugh Hudson", "Ridley Scott"],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Oliver Stone",
  },
  {
    id: 96,
    question:
      "Which sound engineer worked for both Vangelis and Jean-Michel Jarre?",
    options: [
      "Frédérick Rousseau",
      "Raphael Preston",
      "Philippe Colonna",
      "Roger Roche",
    ],
    reason: "Credited on JMJ albums The Concerts in China and Zoolook.",
    answer: "Frédérick Rousseau",
  },
  {
    id: 97,
    question:
      "Blade Runner premiered in the cinemas in 1982. When was Vangelis' soundtrack album released?",
    options: ["1994", "1982", "1983", "2000"],
    reason:
      "It was preceded by an orchestral Blade Runner cover album in 1982, and the release of two original Vangelis BR themes in 1989.",
    answer: "1994",
  },
  {
    id: 98,
    question:
      "Vangelis composed the official anthem of which football World Cup?",
    options: [
      "2002, Korea-Japan",
      "1982, Spain",
      "1990, Italy",
      "1998, France",
    ],
    reason: "The music was released on maxi CD.",
    answer: "2002, Korea-Japan",
  },
  {
    id: 99,
    question:
      "Which track of the Alexander soundtrack album contains a guest performance by violinist Vanessa Mae?",
    options: [
      "Roxane's Veil",
      "Gardens of Delight",
      "Roxane's Dance",
      "Tender Memories",
    ],
    reason:
      "Note that in the film this tune has a different arrangement, without Vanessa Mae.",
    answer: "Roxane's Veil",
  },
  {
    id: 100,
    question: "Most Vangelis solo albums bear this inscription.",
    options: [
      "Composed, arranged, produced and performed by Vangelis",
      "Conceived, orchestrated and realized by Vangelis",
      "Envisioned, scored and created by Vangelis",
      "Written and played by Vangelis",
    ],
    reason: null,
    answer: "Composed, arranged, produced and performed by Vangelis",
  },
];
